So my name is James Smith.
I run multiple seven-figure businesses.
I'm a three-times number one best-selling
author, co-founder of an eight-figure
drinks business,
and I have never in my life done a sales
call.
And if you're someone
that really enjoys doing sales calls,
maybe this isn't the
video for you.
But let's go back a little bit in history.
Twelve years ago, I'm a personal trainer,
I'm in a gym, and we need to do something
called prospecting.
There's a gym with 2,000 members.
I've got zero clients.
I need to talk to literally everyone,
and the objective is to try
and book someone
in for a free session. Now,
this seems easier than converting someone
on a sales
call to do business with you.
But for a lot of people, the gym
is their place where
they put their headphones in,
have a bit of time to themselves,
and what they don't
want is a 24-year-old prick coming up to
them and going, "Excuse me, can I give you
some..." "No, piss off. Leave me alone.
I'm trying to train." Now,
the prospecting wasn't really the hard
part.
The rejection was the hard part.
I've got a thick skin, but talking to 10
people in a row and trying to showcase
your level of expertise to them
and getting
declined all the time, it's deflating.
It's borderline depressing.
You go home, drive home in the car
and just sit in silence.
So social media, for me,
was a way of bypassing that.
I thought,
imagine a world where I could just sit on
my laptop, record on my phone,
and have clients come to me rather than
having to go to them and get rejected.
Here's the honest truth
that not a lot of people really know.
I'm a lot more introverted than people
think.
I spend most of my time working with my
clients in a Discord because social
interactions, phone calls,
they drain the hell out of me.
I don't even take phone calls from my
friends,
so I'm not going to let a stranger
call me up to have me beg them to do
business with me.
And ultimately,
I just think there's a better way for a
lot of people.
Social media, for me,
was a system where I didn't have to
prospect on the gym
floor,
and it got me most of the accolades I
mentioned before.
Now, with sales in business,
I've had over 100,000 people use my app,
sold over a million books,
had over three and a half thousand people
attend talks
in real life.
And my goal from this video is
that some of you, maybe
similar to me, can build a system
that doesn't require having to do sales
calls.
I mapped out a few issues that
are at the top of my mind.
The first thing to address is
that they work, but if it's all you do,
of course it
works. For instance,
let's say you want to develop a wonderful
chest.
If you just did press-ups,
you may never do bench press because you
go, "Well,
James, I do 100 press-ups a day,
and it works." It works,
but there could be a
better way. Am I saying bench press?
You get the drift.
The first thing I like to point out
is something called the empty diary
effect.
When you go to start doing sales calls,
the bigger the bandwidth that you have to
take on the calls,
the emptier your diary looks.
Now,
imagine you call up your local dentist.
You're like, "Yeah,
I've got a filling that I need to have.
I need a dentist." And they go, "Okay,
we can do 9:00 a.m., 9:30
a.m., 10:00 a.m. We can do 11:00 a.m."
And the dentist is free all day,
every day. Straight away, you'd be like,
"Well, why is no one at this dentist?
He must be terrible." Another one.
You're on holiday,
you're walking down a cobbled street.
Someone says, "Hey,
come into my restaurant."
And no one's in there.
All the other restaurants are busy,
but that one's empty.
Think, "No,
that looks like I'm going to get food
poisoning." There's a big issue
with having an empty diary.
And the second thing is
that people then will be scarce
with the amount of hours.
They'll only open up their calendar at
8:30 in the
morning and 4:00 p.m.
in the afternoon to make it look like they
are more in demand
than they are.
But then the availability for people to be
able to reach those
scarce times that you've now put out
are going to mean that some people
are going
to get there.
They could be emotively ready to buy.
They can't get a time slot
that suits them. They bounce.
And bounce is when someone exits the sales
process.
So if your diary's too empty,
you look shit, and if there's not
enough room, they can't book.
And not many of you have got alternative
routes in
which people can go.
Number two would be the time wasters.
Now,
let's say you've got a pretty good close
rate on your sales calls, but two of
them a week, for whatever reason, go,
"I need to think about it.
I need to talk to my wife.
I need to talk to my partner," whatever.
One,
you get that emotional trauma of putting
all that time and effort into
something, and the thing is,
you're stopping other things.
If you're ADHD like me,
if I have something in my diary at 3:00
p.m., that's the
whole day written off. From 1:00 p.m.
onwards, I'm like,
"I've got a call at 3:00." So your
creative juices, your ability
to be free with the day, go do things,
create content, write email marketing
emails,
that's diminished to then jump on the
phone with someone for an hour
for them to go,
"I need to think about it."
When you get three, four, five of those
in a row,
that starts to affect your confidence,
your energy, your aura.
Not to mention, you may think
that wasting two hours a week is fine,
but that adds
up. It's eight hours a month. If you
were to spend that time with a notepad
and pen
writing down good ideas for video content,
writing down good ideas for email
marketing campaigns,
sitting in a room for an hour with a
whiteboard and a pen, you
could come up with ideas
that could drastically change the quality
of your life.
But sitting on a call with someone doing a
podcast that no one's going to listen
to, it's just a waste of time
and energy and effort, and
that time could be spent
better somewhere else. If that
was two hours of strategizing, writing,
planning,
content creation,
as you get better at that,
with each week and month that passes,
you're creating real skills you can take
into the future.
Next thing to keep in mind would be time
zones.
Using the internet gives me to have the
ability to have a global brand.
I can have clients from anywhere.
Azerbaijan, the UK,
Tennessee, Argentina, wherever it is.
If you are going to be scarce
or open your diary at a time that you're
hyper-energized and you're hyped up on
caffeine or whatever it is,
if someone's in
a different time zone
and suddenly it's only open at 4:00 in the
morning, you've
had all this breadth to have this
international business,
and then you've taken it
right down to the same time zone as you
just based on time zones.
The no-shows, which
is there anything worse than a time
waster?
Like I said,
you paused every single part of your day,
and when someone doesn't
show up,
it's not they just haven't showed up.
It's that they've pretty much disrespected
you.
They've gone,
"You weren't even important enough for me
to turn up to the call."
Then we have something called the menu
effect.
Some of you that like to use the sales
calls as a process to sell to people, you
like to keep things off the menu till they
arrive.
You might think in your head it's like the
specials.
Once they've sat at the table,
here's some things
that you might not have seen on
the menu that's a surprise.
But for me as a buyer,
and I like expensive
things. My coach is overqualified.
I stay in nice hotels.
I sit in nice parts of the plane.
I like all the information available to me
so I
can make a decision before.
When I'm going to buy a car,
when I turn up to the
dealership, my mind's already made up.
I don't even need to test drive it.
When I message the salesperson,
"I would like to buy this car.
I'm coming in at 2:00 p.m." First house I
ever went to, I bought.
I'd already made my mind up.
I'm pretty much going there just to make
sure it's
everything that I saw online.
When I go to a restaurant,
already checked the menu.
If you want to run a business where you
keep things off the menu so that you can
sell those things to
that person on the phone call,
you're going to lose buyers
like me. I want information.
I don't care how much it costs.
I don't care about buying. Oh, 10 grand?
Fine.
With the information,
I can make the decision for you so that
if I don't want to
buy,
I will never have to communicate with you
or waste an inkling of your energy
effort to do so. For a lot of you,
rather than jumping on the call,
you could just
say to someone,
"Have a money-back guarantee." I'll be
honest with you.
Some people,
when it comes to my business mentorship,
they go, "James, really want
to help level up my business,
want to get better at social media,
want to make
money online," blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
I literally won't even read the second
half of their email.
I'll go, "Hey, Dave,
you seem like a switched on person.
You're not using a Gmail account, which
is great. How about you join today?
In the first three months,
if you haven't made your money back,
I'll refund you in
full." Now,
no matter what they say from
that period onwards, if they come back
with another long email, I'm like, "Mate,
no, I'm not reading that.
You got the money-back guarantee.
You can either jump in, do it,
use the guarantee, or fuck off." "Oh,
I'd just like
to jump on a call." No,
I'm taking all the risk myself.
If that's not enough,
you're already a fucking headache,
and you've not even joined
the program.
So it's probably better off
that you don't join.
Any single person that needs a sales call,
no, just have a money-back guarantee.
And then if they are someone
that you do need to have a conversation
with, maybe
get them to buy and have an onboarding
call as part of the process.
At least when you turn up on the call,
they've already paid you.
You might have to refund some of them,
but it's going to be a damn sight better
rate than your no-shows
and the time wasters.
Now, a lot of you are thinking, "Yeah,
but other people in my niche do them."
Unless you're a very expensive lawyer
or potentially an accountant taking on a
big
client, unfortunately,
the majority of you are fitness coaches,
and you're copying
what other people do,
what other fitness coaches do.
Now, here's the reason
that other coaches are doing them, right?
There's a lot of mentors in the business
space.
I'm not going to talk shit about them.
Well,
I will talk a little bit of shit about
them.
All of those guys
that you follow in the B2B space have
never made any
money from big coaching businesses.
They've made all their money from teaching
you how to make money.
So they don't know
that much The second thing is,
you've got to understand, for me
to say do sales calls makes my life a lot
easier.
Instead,
I'm making you do the fucking hardest way.
I'm going to go, "Hey,
let's make amazing content.
Let's get good on YouTube.
Let's run email marketing campaigns.
Let's put together a highly converting
landing page." And by the way, there are
assets to get better at all of these
things for free in the description.
To make you a weapon
that doesn't need sales calls, I have to
do so much more work.
Do you understand this?
But the worst thing,
the biggest disservice I could do
is to put an introvert on a
sales call because I know you hate it.
If you hate any part of your business,
you're not just going to keep doing it.
So my life is so much more difficult
because I have to make you a black belt in
email marketing, landing pages,
and all of this.
And then I need to review your landing
pages in the Discord.
Trust me,
I wish I could just shove you lot on
fucking sales calls.
But other coaches
are being told to do it by business
mentors because it is the
easiest way to tell someone to just fuck
off.
Just book them in for a call, and then
if they bounce for the call, whatever
reason, and don't buy, it
was your lead quality
or you didn't sell hard
enough. Here's some closes.
The majority of business gurus in this
space are
just phonies. Now, one thing
that they're getting you to do
is to hide your
pricing. Now, let me tell you this.
I would not have bought my car
if I didn't know the price.
I would not gone to have looked at the
house that I bought if I didn't know the
price.
I would not go to any Michelin star menu
if I couldn't see the pricing.
And I would not stay at any luxury
five-star hotel if they
were not going to show
me the pricing until I'm there.
The idea of hiding your pricing from your
clients
is so fucking stupid, and you
are pushing away top-tier
quality people because they go, "Oh. Oh,
what?
You're not going to show me the pricing
until you get on a call?" Bell end.
And they are bouncing. And the issue
is with this sales process of having a
call is
you are losing so many good quality leads
because you're not giving them what they
want.
There is a world where you do not have to
do sales calls.
You just have to build it,
and it might mean
that you need to get better at some
other skills first.
If you're watching this video right now,
there is an aggressive
Black Friday offer.
I currently have about 52 spaces remaining
for the rest of the
year. And after that,
we close the mentorship down.
Please click on it.
Please consider it.
I help businesses like yours for a living.
And there's a world six months from now
where you make money without having to get
people on sales calls. And when you join,
you go to the Discord, look at
#post-your-wins,
and you'll see the amount of people
that we're already getting
this working for. And
if you did feel personally attacked as a
personal trainer and
you're not ready to join the mentorship
yet, I made this video here where if I had
to start over again
and get to my first 100K a year, this
is exactly how I'd do it.
So check it out.